# Liangyawei Kuang

Room 1007-24, Research Postgraduate Hub, HKUST, Clear Water Bay, Kowloon, Hong Kong. lkuang@connect.ust.hk https://klyw1998.github.io/LiangyaweiKuang/https://www.deadsecond.com

#### Introduction

I am a postgraduate researcher at the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (HKUST). My research goal is to develop learning algorithms and techniques that could endow machines and systems with greater autonomy and intelligence to acquire the skills for executing complex tasks. I am interested in the intersection of reinforcement learning, decision-theoretic planning, and multi-agent systems. Currently, I focus on solving Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning problems under scalability and reliability consideration & diving theoretical and algorithmic foundation of Reinforcement Learning.

# Research Experience

### Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning

Apr. 2021 - present

Self-study and literature review from Multi-Agent Planning Under Uncertainty to Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning (MARL). Implementing basic algorithms on single-agent Planning, single-agent Reinforcement Learning (RL), and MARL. This study is aimed to solve one or more of the key challenges in MARL, including Non-Stationarity, Non-Unique Learning Goals, and Scalability, et al., and explore more theoretical foundations for MARL.

URL Implemented Algorithms on single-agent RL and MARL

Advisor: Prof. Fangzhen Lin

## Multi-Agent Systems

Dec. 2021 - present

Multi-Agent Systems (MAS) research is to study systems that consist of a group of agents that can potentially interact with each other. It was called Distributed Artificial Intelligence which is a classical interdisciplinary research area, including game theory, control, planning, et al., but not only machine learning. This study is to explore more research directions for MARL with the knowledge of classical MAS and other related research areas.

URL Reinforcement Learning for Cooperative Multi-Agent Systems

Advisor: Prof. Fangzhen Lin

#### Education

## HKUST, Hong Kong, China

Aug. 2021 - present

Master of Philosophy in Individualized Interdisciplinary Program

(Robotics and Autonomous Systems)

Advisor: Prof. Fangzhen Lin

# HKUST (Guangzhou), Guangzhou, China

Sept. 2022 - Dec. 2022

Cross Campus Virtual Exchange (Remote)

#### Northeastern University, MA, U.S.A.

Jul. 2020 - Jun. 2021

Thesis-based Master of Computer Engineering in Computer Vision, Machine Learning and Algorithms (degree discontinued)

## University of California, Irvine, CA, U.S.A. Aug. 2019 - Jun. 2020

Final year visiting in Electrical Engineering & Computer Science Department

**Hong Kong Polytechnic University**, Hong Kong, China Jan. 2019 - Jun. 2019 One-semester exchange in Mechanical Engineering Department

	Harbin Institute of Technology, Har Bachelor of Engineering in Mechatronics		Aug. 2016 - Jun. 2020
Teaching	HKUST, Lecturer Multi-Robot Systems Course link: https://www.deadsecond.co	om/teaching	Spring 2022
	Northeastern University, Teaching Assistant Fall 2020 EECS 7311: Two Dimensional Signal and Image Processing		
Skills	Programming Libraries  Languages Mandarin, Classical Chir Others LATEX,	NumPy, I OpenAI Gym nese, English (IELT	MATLAB, R, SQL, Java Matplotlib, Scikit-Learn, n, PyTorch, TensorFlow2 S: 7), Beginner on Latin er, Vim, Microsoft Office
Invited Talks	Cooperative Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning Seminar in Robotics and Autonomous Systems Thrust, System Hub, HKUST(Guangzhou)		
$\mathbf{Projects}$	On-Campus Food Delivery System via Multi-Agent Pathfinding, HKUST Project page: https://github.com/klyw1998/Multi-Agent-Pathfinding		
	Home Credit Default Risk competition at Kaggle, HKUST 2022 Ranked top 14% (Bronze Medal level) based on Machine Learning techniques. This project is carried out by only two participants in less than one week's work! Project page: https://github.com/klyw1998/Statistical-Machine-Learning		
Honours	Postgraduate Studentship, HKUST Meritorious Winner (top 6% in 2019), M Outstanding Student Leader, Harbin Ins Second Class Scholarship, Harbin Institut SMC Scholarship, Harbin Institute of Te	stitute of Technology ite of Technology	